A Guide to the Nimmo United Methodist Church (Virginia Beach, Va.) records,
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Nimmo United Methodist Church (Virginia Beach, Va.) records,
Library of Virginia
54164
.
Nimmo United Methodist Church
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by Nimmo United Methodist Church, Virginia Beach.
Historical Information
Nimmo United Methodist Church was founded in 1791 in Princess Anne County, Virginia, on land purchased from the Nimmo family.
Scope and Content
Records, 1846-1961, of Nimmo United Methodist Church of Virginia Beach, Virginia, consisting of church registers, 1846-1961, containing information on pastors, congregation members, baptisms, and marriages for Nimmo Church, Tabernacle Church, and other Methodist churches in the Princess Anne Circuit, Virginia Conference, Methodist Episcopal Church South and in Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Methodist Episcopal Church South; and minute books, 1886-1938,containing quarterly conference minutes and reports for the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Virginia Conference, Methodist Episcopal Church South.
Contents List
- Church register, 1846-1883 (Volume 1)
  Contains records for the churches in the Princess Anne Circuit, Virginia Conference, Methodist Episcopal Church South, including registers of pastors, registers of members, and baptismal registers, as well as reports on the various churches. Of particular interest is a list of forty-two African American members of Nimmo Church, ca. 1846-1850. Churches listed in the volume: Nimmo, Bear Quarter, Beech Grove, Bethel, Bethesda, Charity, Cutherels, Denby's, Ebenezer, Hickory Ground, Indian Creek, Jerusalem, Knotts Island, Morse's Point, Mosley's, Mount Pleasant, Mount Vernon, Oak Grove, Poplar Neck, Providence, Ropersville, Salem, Tabernacle, West Neck, and Zion.
- Church register, 1884-1887 (Volume 2)
  Contains records for the churches in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Virginia Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, including a register of pastors, register of members, baptismal and marriage registers, and death and disposals register for the churches in the charge. Churches listed in the volume: Nimmo, Beech Grove, Bethel, Charity, Currituck Inlet, Knotts Island, Lynnhaven, Providence, Salem, Sea Beach Mission, Tabernacle, and Wash Woods.
- Church register, 1895-1898 (Volume 3)
  Contains records for the churches in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Virginia Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, including a register of pastors, register of members, baptismal registers, and marriage registers, for the churches in the charge. Churches listed in the volume: Nimmo, Providence, Salem, and Tabernacle.
- Church register, 1898-1904 (Volume 4)
  Contains records for the churches in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Virginia Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, including a register of pastors, register of members, baptismal registers, and marriage registers, for the churches in the charge. Churches listed in the volume: Nimmo, Providence, and Salem.
- Church register, 1904-1915 (Volume 5)
- Church register, 1915-1920 (Volume 6)
  Contains records for the churches in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Virginia Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, including a register of pastors, register of members, baptismal registers, and marriage registers, for the churches in the charge. Churches listed in the volume: Nimmo, Tabernacle, and Wash Woods.
- Church register, 1920-1927 (Volume 7)
  This volume contains many of the same records that are recorded in next two volumes which cover the same span of years--1920-1937 (Nimmo) and 1923-1926 (Nimmo). This volume contains 30 marriage and 6 baptism records not located in those two volumes. Register does not denote at which church these took place.
- Church register, 1920-1937 (Nimmo) (Volume 8)
  Contains records for the churches in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Virginia Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, including a register of pastors, register of members, baptismal registers, and marriage registers, for the churches in the charge. This volume contains a member register for Nimmo Church only.
  This volume contains 45 marriage and 4 baptism records not located in Church Register 1920-1937. Register does not denote at which church these took place.
- Church register, 1923-1926 (Nimmo) (Volume 9)
  Contains records for Nimmo Church in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Virginia Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, consisting of a register members.
- Church register, 1937-1940 (Volume 10)
  Contains records for the churches in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Virginia Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, including a register of members and marriage register for the churches in the charge. Churches listed in the volume: Nimmo and Tabernacle.
- Church register, 1941-1953 (Volume 11)
  Contains church membership register for the churches in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk, District, Virginia Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South. Churches listed in the volume: Nimmo, Salem, and Tabernacle.
- Church register, 1957-1961 (Volume 12)
  Contains records for the churches in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk, District, Virginia Conference of the Methodist Church, including a register of members, and baptismal, marriage, and death registers. Churches listed in the volume: Nimmo and Salem.
- Minute book, 1886-1888 (Volume 13)
  Minute book of the quarterly conferences of the churches in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Virginia Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, containing minutes and reports. Churches listed: Nimmo, Beech Grove, Bethel, Charity, Knotts Island, Lynnhaven, Providence, Salem, and Tabernacle.
- Minute book, 1894-1897 (Volume 14)
  Minute book of the quarterly conferences of the churches in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Virginia Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, containing minutes and reports. Churches listed: Nimmo, Providence, Salem, and Tabernacle.
- Minute book, 1906-1910 (Volume 15)
  Minute book of the quarterly conferences of the churches in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Virginia Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, containing minutes and reports. Churches listed: Nimmo and Tabernacle.
- Minute book, 1910-1914 (Volume 16)
- Minute book, 1915-1918 (Volume 17)
  Minute book of the quarterly conferences of the churches in the Princess Anne Charge, Norfolk District, Virginia Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church South, containing minutes and reports. Churches listed: Nimmo, Tabernacle, and Wash Woods.
- Minute book, 1918-1922 (Volume 18)
- Minute book, 1922-1926 (Volume 19)
- Minute book, 1926-1930 (Volume 20)
- Minute book, 1934-1938 (Volume 21)